In this lecture, we'll learn about an AWS AI service called as Amazon Lex, the AI Chatbot.
Amazon Lex allows you to build and deploy conversational AI interfaces.
So, what it means is that with Amazon Lex, you can build chatbots both for voice and text.
Now, let's try and understand some of the use cases for Amazon Lex.
So, with Amazon Lex, you can build self-service voice-assisted and chatbots.
So, basically, you can build a chatbot which will support your call center.
So, now, let's say, customer has some issue with your product and he wants to raise a complaint.
So, he can do it through a chatbot built using the Amazon Lex.
The next use case is, you can build an application or transaction bot.
So, what this means is, you can build say an application that allows you to order a pizza,
maybe book a hotel or a flight.
Then third one is, you can build an enterprise productivity bot.
So, you can build a chatbot which connects your enterprise data resources which allows your
employees to query the data sources at get a response and then you have the device control bot
which will allow you to use Amazon Lex to issue control commands to the connected device
that you might have within your home or organization.
So, these are some of the use cases for Amazon Lex.
Now, there are some terminologies that you need to understand.
Before, you can build a chatbot using Amazon Lex.
Now, let's take an example.
So, here is a chatbot that helps end users book a hotel.
So, there are four or five key terms that you need to know.
So, one is the intense, then you have utterances, slots, confirmation and fulfillment.
Now, let's try and understand what each of them means.
So, the first one is the intense.
End user comes to this chatbot with some intent or some goal and in this case, because it's
hotel booking app, he will come with intent to book a hotel.
So, that's the intent and when the user comes with the intent, there would be some downstream
action that would be taken by the bot, okay.
So, that's intent.
The next one is the utterance.
It's the spoken or type phrase by the end user that will invoke your intent.
Let's say the user says I would like to book a hotel.
So, this is called as an utterance and what is the intent here to book a hotel.
Now, the third one is slots. So, slots are input data required to fulfill the intent.
My intent was to book a hotel and my utterance was I would like to book a hotel.
Now, if I have to book a hotel, I need at least two details from the end user.
One is which city I want to book the hotel and the second one is the date or dates if it's multiple
days. So, once the user has uttered something like I would like to book a hotel with the intent
to book a hotel, next he is presented with some questions called as slots on and in this case,
which city and which date. So, once the user provides these details, the fourth one is called as
confirmation and this is an example of confirmation. You are summarizing the inputs that he has
provided you and in this case, you can see I will show you want to book a hotel in New York
and he says yes. And then finally, we have our fifth term, which is fulfillment,
which means that your order has been confirmed. And in this case, you can see here he says,
thank you, the reservation went through successfully. So, what you can also do with Amazon Lexus,
you can integrate it to a data source, maybe DynamoDB, RDS or any other data source via
Lambda function. So, it integrates with the Lambda function. So, when the user provides these inputs,
you can make a hotel booking and then get a confirmation number. Along with the thank you,
you can provide the confirmation details here to the user, maybe booking IID or something on those
lines. Now, let us go to the console and let me just show you a quick demo.